

Sabuj Biswas

Front-end Developement Engineer

Front-end developer with 1+ years of experience designing and building responsive web design and web applications. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

xabujbiswas234@gmail.com

Kolkata, India

twitter.com/sabujbiswas234

7384990285

in linkedin.com/in/sabuj-b-78522ba7

github.com/sabuj234

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineer.EGG IoTDE1.0.Development Tata Consultancy Services

04/2021 - Present Kolkata

Modernization of a decade old web application

- Created a custom client dashboard that reduced support tickets by 50%
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 25%
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems
- Presented findings in a clear and concise manner to key decision-makers
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub).

Front-End Developer

Tata Consultancy Services

04/2021 - Present Kolkata
Convert a decade old desktop application into a web application

- Implemented performance tuning techniques on stored procedures and back-end queries which resulted in 46% improvement in application performance
- Worked with an agile team of 12 members and provided endto-end solutions for clients
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-endrelated issues.

EDUCATION

B.SC

Asutosh College

07/2016 - 10/2020

Kolkata

Courses

Physics

- Chemistry

- Mathematics

an College

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JAVASCRIPT

REACT JS

BOOTSTRAP

Git

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Project Name

Connectify - Connect with the world (05/2022 - 06/2022)

- A Social Media made with React JS, Node JS, Express and Mongo DB
- A Social Media web application with photo sharing, following, liking post etc features.
- Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Best Team Award

Awarded with the best team award for converting a decade old desktop application into a web application with React JS and Springboot and delivering the project on time with 60% improvement of user experience and reducing tickets up to 50%.

LANGUAGES

English

Bengali

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

German

Professional Working Proficiency

Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS

Guitar

Chess

Singing